Today, we're gonna talk about the
ontology, what it is, why it
matters, how you actually use it to
build decision-centric systems in
the real world.
So if we think about what is an
ontology? It's the nouns and verbs
that make up your business, right?
So in this manufacturing example, I
have plants and warehouses that
I'm supplying plants from
warehouses, right, I'm shipping
product to customers.
So this really reflects
the grown truth about how your
business is actually operating.
There's complex interconnected
relationships, right.
So. As we model this
into the ontology, the goal is to
actually model how your business
is actually operating, not how these
other systems need it so they can
work.
So, if we think about that in
a decision-centric system, what do I
need to be able to make decisions,
right? I need three things, I need
the data, I need logic,
and I need actions, right, so I need
data, the logic, the actions.
The data represents what the current
state of my business is, the logic
about how do I think about those
things, and the actions I can take
to affect the real world.
Right, so if we can dig into that a
little bit further here on the data
sources, right, I'm connecting to
all my different enterprise systems,
whether they're homegrown, out of
the box software, legacy, new
stuff in the web, doesn't matter.
We have 300 out of box connectors
that you can actually connect to
stuff, or with MMDP, you
can connect to things like Snowflake
and Databricks and BigQuery and
virtualized data that's already
sitting in those enterprise data
lakes and pull it in and just use
that as part of your ontology,
right? So this really is about
making it seamless connecting.
To that data across your business.
Then sources of logic, right?
So these could be really simple.
That could be an Excel spreadsheet,
rules-based logic.
It could be ML models, forecast,
third-party optimizers you bought.
They can be living inside of the
platform, outside of the the
platform. We integrate with all
these different tools no matter
where the model or sources of
the logic are.
We wanna integrate that and actually
model that into the semantic object
about how, for example,
a warehouse works.
What's the logic associated about
how to think about that warehouse?
Then the last is
Systems of action right so if
I think get the data I get the logic
to how to think about it now What
actions can I take and how do I make
it real? So whether it's SAP and
I want to write back to SAP to
create an STO to move product from A
to B across my Network right those
should be modeled in here as the
actions I can take there can be
other things that are on the plant
Floor they can be Financial
systems you name it will connect
into those whether they're legacy or
the on-prem. They're at the edge
They're in the cloud. They can be
web hooks you name it, we connect
with those things to really drive
back those actions into
the enterprise.
So if we bring all the data,
the logic, the action together here,
then I have this ontology that
is very rich, showing me
my actual digital twin of how my
business is operating, how to think
about it with the logic and what
actions I'm gonna take to affect
that system.
So then on top of that,
and we can then build these
workflows and analytics and looks
really are a by-product of the
workflows that I'm building.
So a workflow across many different
business processes or business
systems that I connect together with
the people, the process, and
I really then start to bubble up
the insights there.
And then we start to add other
things in here like automations,
right? So now can we have generative
AI models integrated through AIP
and AIP logic, for example.
That now are helping actually go
reason about it because they have
access to the ontology, the LLM now
has access to context,
not just the data, the context about
how my business operates.
So the LM can have access to
the logic about how to think about
it. So the LM can call a
deterministic model.
It can then drive an action
to write back.
So instead of people having to
swivel chair from a dashboard
over to another tool to figure out
how to make it real, we'll
orchestrate those complex
Actions on the back end to make it
real and that's where really where
automations come in bringing
reasoning into this process
and ontology really is that
Context of how your business is
operating because the LMS were not
trained on your business's data or
processes
is the products in SDK.
So this is where we can build data
products, rich applications, whether
that's in a mobile app for the
plant floor, it's a custom
React app to interact with my
customers, or it could be through
the ontology SDK, where I actually
create a custom SDK of
my ontology.
So an SDK of business
and business process that I can
build different applications, back
integrations, I can integrate that
SDK that has agented workflows.
Into my existing applications.
Lots of different and really great
stuff that you can do by powering
different SDKs throughout
your business.
This really opens up the way that
you integrate it and really improves
the usability, which improves speed
and time to value.
So all of this comes together with
the goal of AI and humans
working together on the ontology.
And the goal over time is to
automate more and more of your
business, so really what you need is
the ontolgy to model the data, the
logic, the actions to drive
decisions in your business